## Michael O'Rourke

Product Manager for Cloud, Web, and Digital Marketplaces

**TOWN** Dallas, Texas **PHONE** 512-740-4491

**EMAIL** <u>cale.orourke@gmail.com</u> **LINKEDIN** linkedin.com/in/caleorourke

Forward-thinking product manager with experience managing the strategy and execution for cloud, web, and digital products. Solid reputation for hatching profitable strategies, aligning business and development pillars, and taking new products from concept, to design, to development, to delivery.

Tech-savvy and analytical with a background in product and program management, front-end design, and software development. Adept at building diverse, high-tech products in fast-paced environments. Additional qualifications:

- 15 years in Product Management and Software Development
- Working knowledge of Agile, Lean, DevOps and Offering Management
- Degree in Management Information Systems
- Certified Product Owner, PMP, ScrumMaster and several others
- Proficiency with HTML/CSS, Jekyll, jQuery, LESS, Node and SQL
- Continuing education in Information Technology

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Product Portfolio Manager**

IBM CLOUD, 2012 – Present Dallas. Texas

Pivot product initiatives and market strategies toward developing a growing cloud computing platform. Responsible for building and launching new cloud PaaS and laaS products in global marketplaces.

- Establish new vertical products in Bluemix, SoftLayer, and IBM marketplace catalogs
- Craft business cases, proofs-of-concept, and requirements for dev consumption
- Enact strategies to reach untapped markets and new growth opportunities
- Capture market demands and architect plans to ensure "whole product" success
- Align technology roadmaps and P&L to drive organic growth and achieve business objectives
- Work directly with developers, designers, and customers to transform user/buyer needs into empathic feature-sets

#### **Senior Product Manager**

NEOPOST ID, 2003 – 2012

Austin, Texas

Cultivated pipelines to new markets and designed offerings for new online solutions and native apps. Responsible for customer-facing SaaS, on-premise, and digital products.

- Reached new markets by transitioning native products to hosted ecosystems
- Facilitated technology refresh programs to eliminate churn and increase revenue flow
- Adopted new Agile and Product Portfolio practices, reducing time-to-market by 40%
- Managed \$25M project to transform line-of-business apps into a hosted CRM environment
- Launched storefront for purchasing Internet-enabled apps on smart devices, increasing attachment rates 30-32% each quarter

#### **Technical Project Consultant**

SPRINT NEXTEL, 2000 – 2002 Plano. Texas

Spearheaded retail launches for mobile products and provided operational support for system hardware, networks, and back-office systems.

- Ushered in technology induction programs for ION broadband, 3G, and new mobile devices
- Coordinated new firmware builds, onsite implementations, and system updates during planned/unplanned maintenance windows
- Gathered quantitative data to report failures and serviceability issues

# .....

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **B.S.**, Information Technology

LIBERTY UNIVERSITY

Advanced studies in digital imaging, graphic design, security, web and software integration, networking, and enterprise technology.

#### A.A., Management Information Systems

LIBERTY UNIVERSITY

Core foundations of technology, application software, current programming languages, and managing developmental cycles in business environments.

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

#### **Practical Product Management Certified**

PRAGMATIC MARKETING

### **Project Management Professional (PMP)**

PROJECT MANAGEMENT INSTITUTE

#### **Certified Scrum Product Owner**

SCRUM ALLIANCE

#### **Certified Scrum Professional**

SCRUM ALLIANCE

#### Certified ScrumMaster

**SCRUM ALLIANCE** 

#### **Network+ Certified**

COMPTIA